Some windings work just like Tesla transformers.
Here's the winding, the inductor.
That's the amplifier for the signal generator.
The driver.
Logic for protecting the generator.
And the switch.
Battery, power supply.
Here we'll be monitoring the signal on the drain of the transistor.
And that's the frequency.
The frequency of the LC resonance of this circuit.
But the duty cycle of the signal will be equal to the length of a signal that would correspond to the wave processes in these coils.
We start it up.
This is the consumption.
12 volts.
1.5 amps, a little less.
This is the signal on the drain.
Amplitude 276, duty cycle 3.7%.
In continuous mode.
That's the kind of peak we're hitting it with.
The cold end of the coil is connected to grounding in hot air.
Let's run a neon bulb past it.
It starts to glow.
And in the zone of the reverse turns it glows very brightly.
Let's take the hot end and light up the lamp.
The lamp lit up.
Right now the coil is forming a standing wave in the space around it.
A longitudinal one.
The camera doesn't show it, but right now the glow on the lamp is alternating between.
There are bright bands and dimmer ones.
This glow shows the geometry of the longitudinal standing wave around this winding.
You can see that touching it with your hand has an effect.
When you connect the hot end, the glow is much stronger.
It gets stronger if you move this fluorescent lamp away from the coil.
The glow can be observed even with the grounding disconnected.
The coil will work as a quarter wave.
As you can see, there's a glow.
It also increases when you touch it.
And with the coil grounded, the glow will be brighter.
We ground it.
It increases, which indicates that this resonator is matched with the length of the grounding cable.